Finding Aid for the Richard Montague papers LSC.0264
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 5: Subject Files
  - Moschovakis. (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Mutual interpretability vs. mutual relative interpretability. (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Mutual interpretability vs. mutual relative interpretability (old). (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Meetings Stanford workshop on grammar and semantics of natural language., 1970 - September & November. (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Meetings - September, November. Stanford Materials III - most interesting. Also contains some comments. (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Meetings - Stanford., Materials Moravcsik, with my notes & comments on mass terms., September, November 1970 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Meetings - Stanford workshop papers: Partee & Suppes & Moravcsik & my comments. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Meetings -, Stanford Materials I., September, November 1970 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Meetings -, Stanford Materials 2., September, November 1970 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Meetings - Amsterdam, general assembly. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Meetings -, Warsaw, abstracts & notes., Summer 1959 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Meetings - Berkeley & Europe., Summer 1963. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Meetings - Helsinki., Summer 1962. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Meetings - model theory symposium., Summer 1963 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Meetings - Oxford symposium., Summer 1963 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Meetings - Stanford Congress. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Meetings - Israel., Summer 1964. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Meetings - Amsterdam Congress, abstracts & notes from talks & programs., Summer 1967 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Meetings - Los Angeles, set theory institute., Summer 1967 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Meetings - Los Angeles, institute on set theory, handwritten notes & edited notes., Summer 1967 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Meetings - Los Angeles, set theory institute, mimeoed notes., Summer 1967 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Meetings - Vienna, 1968. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Meetings - New Orleans ASL [Association for Symbolic Logic]., personal., January 22-23 1969 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Meetings - Israel., June 1970 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Meetings - ASL., Atlantic City, personal., January 1971 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Meetings - Department of Linguistics and Philosophy, UCLA., May 1971 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Meetings - Bucharest, International Congress., August/ September 1971 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - [Miscellaneous (1st drawer - desk in Dwinelle)?]. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous notes [abstracts]. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, preservable things. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - [Montague collection: Bequest of the Montague estate., 1971]. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - [Montague's personal - doctoral program]. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - [Montague's personal - program for organ concert]. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - [Montague, Richard (personal, professional correspondence)]. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - [Montague's personal - Homework in Math 235.], [1952-1953]. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - [National Science Foundation - Research Metamathematics., 1968]. (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - New Mexico class., March 1967. (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Niemi, Gunna. (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Nominalism. (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Non-finite axiomatizability: 1. talk before AMS 2. additional notes ... 3. some notes ... unimportant. (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Non-finite axiomatizability (notes which are probably of no importance). (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Non-finitizable & essentially abstract, also some miscellaneous note on non-finite axiomatizability. (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Notes on articles & books. (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - [Notes on colloquia talks, 1970-1971]. (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Notes from my talk at Cornell, manuscript of abstract. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - NSF - proposal submitted,()., November 1964 (Box 27, Folder 2-3)
  - Old things. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - On the definition of formal deduction. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - On the nature of number. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - On the notion of interpretability. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - On the paradox of grounded classes. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Opportunities for travel & visiting appointments. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Orbis. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Organ combos. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - A paradox regained. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Personal mementos --- Includes 3 passports. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - [Philosophical notes, miscellaneous., September 1970]. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - [Philosophy notes, miscellaneous., October 1970- ]. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy notes taken while a student. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Physics 4A. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Poems, story fragments. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Pragmatics (paper), manuscript. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Pragmatics & intensional logic, manuscript. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Pragmatics & intensional logic, Dana's modal logic. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Pragmatics ditto masters. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Pravity seminar. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Predicate calculus - Montague. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Predicate calculus, rarified. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Predicate calculus: On Tarski's formalization ... (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Predicate calculus: On Tarski's formalization ... early drafts. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Predicate calculus: On Tarski's formalization ... connected material & letters. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Predicate calculus (Tarksi, Monk). (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Predicate calculus w/terms. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Predicate calculus (with op[eration]. sym[bol]'s and/or descr. phrases). (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Prediction paradox. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Prelims. [Qualifying exams with comments]. (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
  - Preliminary exams, old. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Printed matter, miscellaneous, which has been read. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Prior comments on philosophers & students. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Prior, objects of thought. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Probability & intituitionism. (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Problems, preliminary questions (& miscellaneous questions). (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - [Professional correspondence to RM]. (Box 29, Folder 14-15)
  - Project correspondence. (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Proofs of miscellaneous theorems. (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Publications, printed references to me, programs, of meetings, recital programs, vita. (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Publishers & publishers' representatives & literary agents -, before 1969. (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Putnam's problem. (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Ramsey's theorem. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Rank, notion of (summary of talk which never been given, summarizing novelties of MST. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Real closed fields. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Real numbers, construction of. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Recipients of papers and reprints (lists). (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Recursion theory monograph - old. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Recursion theory as a brand of model theory, manuscript. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Recursion theory: Gandy & Barwise, UCLA class., Winter & Spring 1968. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Recursion theory (generalized) and weak 2nd order logic, old things. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - [Recursion theory, miscellaneous notes]. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Recursion theory as a branch of modal theory - ditto masters. (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Referee's report. (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Referee's report: F.G. Asenjo. (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Referee's report: Bunder's thesis. (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Referee's report: Cobham's paper. (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Referee's report: J.L. Cohen (first & second versions). (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Referee report: Gabbay. (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Referee's report: miscellaneous. (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Referee's report: Hunter. (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Referee's report: G. Stahl. (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Referee's report: R.M. Jones (or fragments, thereof). (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Referee's report on R.M. Jones' paper (notes on it). (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Referee's report: S. Kiss' papers. (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Referee's reports: van Fraassen. (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Referee's reports: Leblanc, 1967. (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Referee's report: D. Pager (sent to A.R. Anderson). (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Referee's report: Robert Rogers. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Referee's report: Brown & Stuermann. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Referee's report: Gerald B. Standley. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Referee's report: Vickers proposal. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Referee's report: W.L. Zlot. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Requirement revision. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Referee's report. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    SEE Mailings of reprints [reference only - empty folder].
  - Research grants. (Box 31, Folder 9)
    SEE ALSO Fellowships & research grants October '70 [reference only - empty].
  - Retirement fund, social security. (Box 31, Folder 10)
    Personal items removed to restricted Box 41.
  - Reviews: general information for reviewers. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Reviews of Leblanc. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Reviews of Martin. (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Review of Martin: Intension and decision. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Reviews: Morris and Resnikoff. (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Reviews of Simon. (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Review of Tucker. (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Review of Wang: Arithmetic translations of axiom systems ... relevant letters from Church. (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Review of Wang: Between number theory and set theory. (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Review of Wang. (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Reviews of recitals in which I have participated, letters of appreciation for same, --- Announcements for same, invitations to play same, some church programs. (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Robinson's seminar., Spring 1963. (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Robinson's informal seminar, 1963-1964. (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Role of formal logic. (Box 31, Folder 24)
    SEE Philosophy of language .. the role of formal logic --- Reference only - empty folder].
  - Rules of thumb, infallible. (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Rutgers University. (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Sabbatical. (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Sabbatical., August 1962-January 1963. (Box 31, Folder 28)
    SEE ALSO: Univerity policies & procedures.
  - Savage. (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Schonfield, recursion theory, mimeo of notes from UCLA class., Fall 1967. (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Schonfield, recursive theory, notes on lectures at UCLA., Fall 1967. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Schnitt's proof. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Scientific notes, miscellaneous. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Scientific notes, miscellaneous, before 1955. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Scott: cumulative theory of types. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Scott: interpolation theory. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Separability. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Set theory. (Box 32, Folder 8)
    SEE ALSO Higher order logic: set theory [reference only - folder empty] and Talks, John Dover, 23 February 1967 (higher order operations or ordinals.
  - Set theory: higher card operations ()., April 1967- (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Set theory: miscellaneous notes., April 1967-. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Set theory: gen'd cont. hyp. a possible proof. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Set theory: Grewe's summary of Goedel's monograph. (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Set theory: higher operations. (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Set theory: justification (begun )., May 1964 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Set theory: Cantor's absolute. (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Set theory: Cohen's proof. (Box 32, Folder 16-17)
  - Set theory: foundations of ()., Summer 1964 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Set theory: Reflection principles & closure principles. (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Contributions to axiomatic foundations of set theory (manuscripts). (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Higher order logic: set theory & 2nd order logic ... (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Shelah, lectures, August 1970. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Sigma Ki. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Singular sentences. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Smith, Perry. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Smith, Perry. Dissertation, version, also, parts of older versions., 12 May 1970 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Sobel. (Box 33, Folder 6-9)
  - Staal. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Stairway problem. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Standard models of set theories and ranks of set theories. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Stencils (Philosophy 187B). (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Stockholm:, Spring 1966. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Suppes: Talk at Popper's London seminar., June 14, 1966. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Suppes (mimeographed material on set theory). (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Syntactical treatments of modality: hangman paradox, etc. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - System of Stupecki. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - [Talks, possible]. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Tarski: talk on cylindric algebra. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - [Tarski] at Stanford on the measure problem. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - [Tarski symposium]. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Tarski: seminar on the decision problem, Winter 1967. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - That talk to Philos. Club., December 1, 1961. (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Theories not finitely axiomatizable (loose scribbles). (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Texts: trial offers. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Theories which are not finitely axiomatizable (copy 1). (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Theories which are not finitely axiomatizable, manuscripts & typed copy --- Accompanying typed footnotes & title page for thesis. (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Theories which ... [theorem 6 ?] ... (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Theories which ... [theorem 8?], manuscript & typescript. (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Theories which ... [theorem 9?], manuscript & typed copy. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Theories which are not finitely axiomatizable, manuscript. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Theories which are not finitely axiomatizable (portable kit). (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Theories which are not ... old footnotes, memoranda. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Theories which ... [theorem 2] (predicate calculus), manuscript & typescript. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Theory of models: Chang's seminar. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Thesis (general). (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Towards a general theory of computability / and using machines. (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Travel grants. (Box 35, Folder 9)
    SEE Fellowships, research grants & travel grants [reference only - empty folder].
  - Travel information, travel agents, obsolete currency converter. (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Travel applications: Montague. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Travel expenses. (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Travis. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Travis, Larry: dissertation, first uncorrected draft, pp.1-199. (folder 1 of 2). (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Travis, Larry: dissertation, first uncorrected draft (pp.200-402). (folder 2 of 2). (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Tripodes, Peter: M.A. thesis. (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Two contributions to the foundations of set theory by Richard Montague. (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Undecidability of integration theory. (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - U.S. National Committee - service as member of USNC. (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - [USNC - miscellaneous]. (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - U.S. National Committee constitution, most recent. (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - U.S. National Committee constitution, old. (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - U.S. National Committee 5th annual meeting in Washington., personal., 1962 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - U.S. National Committee meeting, personal., 1964 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - U.S. National Committee meeting., 1965 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - U.S. National Committee meeting, personal., 1965 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - U.S. National Committee meeting (including proposals) for travel money to Amersterdam., 1966 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - U.S. National Committee meeting., 1967 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - U.S. National Committee meeting., 1968 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - U.S. National Committee meeting., 1969 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - U.S. National Committee membership lists. (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - U.S. National Committee minutes of full committees and sub-committees. (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - U.S. National Committee service as chairman of LMPS sub-committee. (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - U.S. National Committee Amsterdam Congress, excerpts. (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - U.S. National Committee Amsterdam Congress & USNC preparations for it. (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - U.S. National Committee Amsterdam letters to industry., 1967 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Vaught - Montague paper, old. (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Vaught - Montague, final typescript together with corrections. (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Vaught - Montague paper, manuscript, old version. (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Vaught - Montague paper, carbons, old version. (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Vlach. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Wald, notes on, Die Widerspruchs, Ergebuisse eines math Koll., vol.8 (), pp.38-72., 1935-1936 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Warsaw., 1961. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Weber dissertation. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Wisdom, J. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Yale. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Yost. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Cocciarella 1. (Box 38, Folder 8-9)
  - [Linguistics - Partes paper]. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Morewedge, Parviz: A study in Ibn Sina's metaphysical system, 1-6. (folder 1 of 3). (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Morewedge, Parviz: A study in Ibn Sina's metaphysical system, translation. (folder 2 of 3). (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Morewedge, Parviz: A study in Ibn Sina's metaphysical system, notes & glossary. (folder 3 of 3). (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - An axiomatic development of set theory - Appendix 1 (logical). (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - An axiomatic development of set theory - rank-free axioms for set theory. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - An axiomatic development of set theory, Appendix 1: stencils. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - An axiomatic development of set theory - some questions of cardinality. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - An axiomatic method (symposium), programs, & abstracts [empty]. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Restricted Material
    - Retirement fund, social security --- Material removed from box 31, folder 10 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      CONSULT W/MANUSCRIPTS LIBRARIAN REGARDING RESTRICTION.
    - Philosophy 126 [148], philosophy of science, student notes., Spring 1960 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      Graded papers removed from box 7, folder 4. CONSULT W/ MANUSCRIPTS LIBRARIAN REGARDING RESTRICTION.
- Series 6: Addition, 1948-1972
  Scope and Content
  This series contains materials added to the collection in 2013. Materials in this series include personal correspondence, Montague's coursework from Berkeley, genealogical notes, and NSF grant forms.
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1954-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Regarding Montague's Death, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Genealogical Forms, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mailing Lists, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Montague's Coursework, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Science Foundation Grants, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Organ Ephemera, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Secretary Notes, Association for Symbolic Logic, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Various Berkeley/San Francisco Newspapers, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)